Mileide Silva

Front-End Developer | Wordpress

My Experience & Skills

I'm a Front-End Developer with experience working both independently and with teams. I'm all about delivering great results and finding creative ways to showcase businesses. I love learning new tech and keeping up with trends to improve my work. I care about writing clean, efficient code and building user-friendly experiences. I'm also a good listener, always making sure clients' needs are at the heart of every project.

Relevant Experience

Front-end Engineer WordPress - Zucalab Design, Innovation & eCommerce Solutions São Paulo, Brazil (Remote) • February 2024 — Present

- · WordPress Development;
- · Website Maintenance using Next.js, TypeScript, and React;
- Projects development in WordPress (Creating a theme from scratch, plugins maintenance, WooCommerce, and Gutenberg Blocks);
- · Specialist in finding solutions to problems;

Front-end Engineer WordPress - FutureLab Digital Web Design & eCommerce Platforms

Auckland, New Zealand (Remote) • October 2021 — September 2023

- Development of projects in WordPress (Creating a theme from scratch, plugins maintenance, WooCommerce, and Gutenberg Blocks);
- · Cross-browser and responsive development with pixel-perfect validation;
- · Specialist in finding solutions to problems;
- \bullet Management of projects from receiving customer requests to final response;
- Self-management of demands;
- $\hbox{\bf \cdot} \ {\it Organization of customer requests (As an a/Productive.io);}$
- · Delegate demands to other departments;
- Response to customers from different countries;
- Support resolving issues for the international client base (Zendesk).

WordPress Developer - Performance Foundry

Auckland, New Zealand (Remote) • May 2021 — October 2021

- Management of projects in WordPress;
- $\bullet \ \mbox{Wireframe creation and UI/UX enhancements};$
- · Support and Migration Specialist;
- · Resolving issues for international client base.

Front-End Developer - VZ Lab

São Paulo, Brazil • October 2018 — September 2020

- Development of webpages in JavaScript/ES6, Vue.js, Three.js, GSAP, 8th Wall, and SASS;
- Instagram filter creation in Spark AR;
- Creation of ads in HTML5 using Google Web Designer (GWD);
- Product documentation for numerous clients in the company's portfolio.

Junior Front-End Developer - Wunderman Thompson

São Paulo, Brazil • August 2017 — September 2018

• Website maintenance and creation of landing pages using jQuery, HTML5, SASS, CSS3, and GIT (Client: Vivo).

São Paulo - Brazil verdemima@gmail.com +55 11 96730-1226 github.com/mimaverde https://www.linkedin.com/in/mileidesilva

Skills

HTML - CSS3 - JavaScript - WordPress
Development - RESTful APIs - Tailwind CSS Vue.JS - GraphQL - Responsive Design Performance Optimization - Search Engine
Optimization - Front-End Development - Version
Management (GIT) - Code Debugging Troubleshooting - Organization - Documentation

Educational

BSc - Internet Systems Development FIAP - São Paulo, Brazil January 2014 - December 2015

Associate's degree - Web Design

Senac - São Paulo, Brazil January 2007 - December 2009

Associate's degree - Graphic Design ETEC José Rocha Mendes January 2005 - June 2006

Certifications

EF SET English Certificate 68/100 (C1 Advanced) EF Standard English Test (EF SET) - July 2024

Photoshop: Introduction to Software SAGA - July 2023

Front-end Development - 132h Alura - March 2017

JavaScript: Programming in the Language of the Web

Alura - February 2017

WordPress: Creating a Theme from Scratch Alura - January 2017

Language

Portuguese Native English Advanced C1 (EF SET)